Zachary Branson

SOFTWARE ENGINEER



(936) 676-5542



Zac21261@gmail.com



Linkedin.com/in/zac-branson



12106 Jamie Dr. Manor, Tx 78653



https://zacharybranson.com

PROFILE

I am 27 years old, and currently a Software Engineer at Modernize. I have been married to my wife Danica, and we recently had our first child Emma. I am a hard-working, detailed programmer, looking for new opportunities to use my skills and expand my knowledge as a Software Engineer. I am extremely passionate about being great software developer, and I'm always working hard to expand my knowledge in the field. In my career, I have had the opportunity to contribute to many large projects spanning numerous areas of the products/API's I've worked on. These contributions have improved performance, and overall functionality of the business. I look forward to meeting and learning how I might be a part of your organization.

EDUCATION

Stephen F. Austin University

Bachelor's of Science **Computer Science** 2012 - 2017

TECHNOLOGIES

PHP / Laravel MySQL Microsoft SQL Server JavaScript / JQuery HTML / CSS Doctrine

TOOLS

Horizon

Redis

Docker Jenikns Bamboo Kibana Postman Git Codeception

SKILLS

PHPUnit

Object Oriented Programming

Team Collaboration Great Problem Solver Excellent Communicator

WORK EXPERIENCE

SOFTWARE ENGINEER II

Modernize | Austin, Tx | 2019 - Current

Currently working at Modernize as a Full Stack Software Engineer for all core business needs. I assist in building, improving, and maintaining high traffic, web based API's that are used by multiple sites our business owns. These services are written in PHP using the Laravel framework with a MySQL database. Work closely with other departments to always refine our user experience and overall make our product better.

SENIOR SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Mattersight | Austin, Tx | 2017 - 2019

Worked to improve and maintain a large-scale enterprise web application. I had the opportunity to work on major projects that improved the functionality and performance of the product. I worked as a full stack developer, with responsibilities that scaled from front-end, back-end / API development, and database management.

WEB APPLICATION DEVELOPER

Elevation | Remote | 2017 - 2017

Built and maintained a social media like mobile application for staff to track fitness, nutrition, and bible studies. Users have the ability post achievements, add profile pictures, and comment on posts. I built using the Laravel PHP framework with a MySQL backend. I used HTML, CSS, and JQuery for the front-end development.

REFERENCES

Seth Findley Manager of Capture & Analytics Mattersight Phone / (913) 832-4925 Email / seth.findley@gmail.com

Lea Yousoufov Senior Software Engineer Spring Health Phone / (718) 916-2246 Email / lea.yousoufov@gmail.com